# 

#### **CONTACT**

E-mail: guo.t@northeastern.edu Git-hub: github.com/guo-felicia Linkin: in/feliciaguo Porfolio: feliciahi.wixsite.com/

#### **SKILLS**

#### Languages:

Java,Python,SQL,R,CSS, JavaScripts,XML, HTML,React

#### **Softwares & Tools:**

Docker, Git Hub, Git-Flow, PaaS, Node. js, npm, Kubernetes, Homebrew

#### **Design Tools:**

Illustrator, In Design, Photoshop,

#### INTRODUCTION

#### Hi, I am Felicia.

I am a creative and developer originally from China. I love working with technology and design. My passion is to help companies to their goals most effectively and be more competitive in the future market place. I believe that programming is a way of thinking and a way to achieve all crazy ideas. And a programmer with design experience and strong creativity can achieve the maximum integration of any project work. We are a bridge and a connecting point. Our presence makes future technology more user-friendly and more attractive to consumer groups.

"Don't wait for the last judgement, it takes place everyday."

-- Albert Camus.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Alibaba Group Software Engineer

Hangzhou CHINA 2020.8 – Present

Built and designed both the front-end and back-end of the IEB (Intelligent Entrepreneur Brain) project to support the function of recording the daily work time of staff.

Synchronized the code with other team members through Git-Flow.

Critiqued the code at the end of week and wrote tests to debug the code before moving to work on the new function.

Created mocked data to test the code, the tools used are MySQL, Docker etc.

Conducted product research and collected user's feedback to improve the design of the product and updated some functions.

#### Skills:

Java - back-end programing
React - front-end website programing
Python - data manimulating
Git-Flow - Synchronized the code for
teamworks
Sourcetree - view the git commit

#### **Applications:**

VScode, IntelliJ IDEA, Docker, MySQL Workbench etc.

#### **Projects:**

IEB (Intelligent Entrepreneur Brain) project to support the function of recording the daily work time of staff.
Create a website for showing all and latest Develop Logfile of team.

# MIND Lab Boston USA (Music, Imaging and Neural Dynamics Lab) Research Assitant 2019.11 – 2021.1

Used Matlab to manipulate the raw data and wrote R scripts for data visualization.

Created and developed the online tests for all lab experiments, the tools used are Qualtrics, Python-based Psycho Pi, VS Code etc.



"Persistence makes you see what others can't see."

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# MIND Lab Boston USA (Music, Imaging and Neural Dynamics Lab) Research Assitant 2019.11 – 2021.1

Run participants for the Synchrony Gamma project and the Norzandan project.

Helped develop the current Lab web page, and wrote wiki pages for giving the instructions of some projects.

#### Skills:

Matlab - data manipulating
R - data visualization
Python - code for cognition test used in research

#### **Applications:**

Qualtrics, Python-based Psycho Pi, VS Code, Git Hub etc.

#### **Projects:**

Synchrony Gamma project. Norzandan project.

#### IBM UI/UX Designer

Jining China 2019.5 – 2019.8

Generated an interactive primary version of the product pre-development which is used for tracking the behavior and status of employers, enabling the user to test the main interactions of the product.

Organized content within the EMR app and its website to provide the user with an effective information architecture to guide the user to accomplish tasks.

#### Skills:

Balsamiq Wireframes - low fidelity prototype InDesign - hierarchy and typology study Figma & Adobe XD - Interactive prototype design and illustration



"The greatest glory in living lies not in never falling, but in rising every time we fall." -Nelson Mandela

#### **EDUCATION**

2019.9 – 2023 (Graduation Year)

Northeastern University Honors Program Khoury College of Computer Sciences

B.S. Computer Sciences & Design

Honors: GPA 3.86/4.0

Dean's List

Recipient of Honor Student Scholarship.

#### Courses:

#### Computer Science:

Software development Teachnology and Human Values OOD (Object-oriented programming and design) Database design Algorithm Discrete Structure

#### Design:

Typology Design 1 & 2 Interaction Design 1 web & 2 mob Information Design 1 & 2 Programming Basics (front-end programming) 5D Design

Organization: Leadership Living Learning Community, CSS Outreach Department, debate club, Food recovery club.

2018.6 - 2018.8

**Cornell University** Computer and Information School

GPA 3.90/4.0

Courses: MatLab, HCI(intro), Ethic of Tech

2018.1 - 2018.2

MIT - Massachusetts Institute of Technology Robotic Engineer of the Hydrodynamics fields

GPA 3.75/4.0

Courses: C++, Arduino, Dynamics and Fluid mechanics



"The way to get started is to quit talking and begin doing."

-Walt Disney

#### **PROJECTS**

#### **Computer Science:**

2020.10 -- 2020.12

#### SHAKESHAPES

#### Java Program - Animations

This is a java animator application. The classic Model-View-Controller architecture is used to build this application progressively.

The model represents animations and supports various kinds of 2D shapes. A text description of the animation will be produced to record each animation.

The View is an interface; particular concrete views implements that common interface.

Supporting views:

- Txt word description
- SVG
- Java animation (classic, interactive, discrete - continuous, Slo-Mo etc.)

The visual view can played through animation referring to players' instruction.

2020.9 -- 2020.10

# Pyramid Solitaire Game Java game

This is a classic java game - Pyramid Solitaire. The benefits of the model-view-controller architecture shine when we add new features, by isolating relevant parts of our design and changing them independently.

The model in a program represents the game state, the controller 'runs" the program, effectively facilitating it through a sequence of operations.

- Flexible design for variations of the game: Pyramid Solitaire with easier rules. If a card is covered by only one oother card and the player can remove those two cards as a pair ( pair is 13 as desired).
- Multi-pyramid shapes (paly the game with double deck)



Life is what happens when you're busy making other plans."

-John Lennon

#### **PROJECTS**

#### **Computer Science:**

2020.4 - 2020.5

#### Fridges Never Lie Health APP (mobile) & Database design

This project is about health management for users, focusing on database design to support basic functions the app have such as to record daily meal plans and to track the expiration date of food in fridges.

The goal of this project is to avoid unnecessary domestic food waste.

The tasks included:

- Created user personas and conducted user research.
- Designed the data frame for supporting all functionalities (MySQL)
- Designed user flows and wireframes to represent the user's journey as they interact with the app. (Figma/Bottlenose)

2020.4

#### Minesweeper Java game

Minesweeper is a single-player puzzle video game. The objective of the game is to clear a rectangular board containing hidden "mines" or bombs without detonating any of them, with help from clues about the number of neighboring mines in each field.

- Cells have three states: uncovered, covered and flagged.
- A covered cell is blank and clickable, while an uncovered cell is exposed.
- Flagged cells are those marked by the player to indicate a potential mine location.



" I let my hands do the talking."

#### **PROJECTS**

#### Design:

2020.10 - 2020.12

#### SubWe!

#### UI/UX design

SubWe! is a website providing real-time public transit data and nearby recommandations to fullfill all the transit needs during the trip.

SubWe! was designed for aggregating and mapping real-time public transit data, crowd-sourcing user data to determine the true location of buses and trains, managing the card and travel plans to provide best service for personal transition.

#### **Prototype includes:**

Project landing page
Log in / Sign up page
Home page (anonymous and log in)
Workflow - 1 - planning the trip
Workflow - 2 - checking my wallet
Workflow - 3 - viewing my favorite trips

Color Pattern: Grapefruit red & Berlin blue

**Styles:** "Calm yet full of vitality", "Geometric elements", "simple"

Inspirations: I love cities, smells, noise, the atmosphere that is different every time. And I know subway station is such as place, people travels everyday. Even though people are always busy while traveling, I hope when they need some helps and open my website, the color and all interactive design could To please them, the large-scale use of orange-pink, let them escape the usual single visual fatigue, and make every experience interesting and refreshing.

2020.11 -- 2020.12

#### My Zine Process book

My Zine shows my skills of writing / documentation / visual design / book layout / explaining design decisions / identifying bias.

Color Pattern: [All gradiant] Electric blue & Lemon & Raspberry & Ultramarine

Styles: Modern & Comtemporary



"The future belongs to those who believe in the beauty of their dreams."

-Eleanor Roosevelt

#### **PROJECTS**

#### Design:

2020.10 -- 2020.12

#### 1960-1990 Modern Year book (75 page+)

In this project, it requires the ability of reading, sketching, editing, and developing grids in master page to effectively present text and image throughout the length of this 75+ page book. it will be a constant challenge, often to the very end, neither idea or criteria can be sacrificed for the other or the design will be commonplace.

2020.9 -- 2020.11

# I have nothing to say Typography poster ( typo concepts and definitions)

The core of this project is to perfect a visual dialogue between structured and unstructured typographic elements within a frame – composing ideal relationships between type as image and type as information/text.

2020.2 -- 2020.3

# Yolo - Website Design (HTML, CSS, JavaScripts)

Create an online canvas which allows the user to free their mind by doing meaningless interaction with the screen. (JavaScript, D3, CSS,VS Code)the user's mouse.

2020.1 -- 2020.3

# CHICHA MENU Chinese Resturant Menu Design

Create a menu for Chinese resturant with strong Chinese identity by using traditional flower pattern and the theme of the menu refers to the knowledge of Solar term.



"When you reach the end of your rope, tie a knot in it and hang on." -Franklin D. Roosevelt

#### Research

#### World Issue and Human Values:

#### Do you really know about MARIJUANA?

The article focuses on drug abuse. The sources referenced are the song "Hotel California", an article pub lished by National Institution on Drug Abuse, and a blog about marijuana legalization and regulation. From these materials I found that western countries are more tolerant towards marijuana compared to the Asian ones. Since blog is widely used and effectively targeted at a particular community, I plan to write a blog to provide both sides of marijuana, combining with relevant historical facts to explain the difference. Hopefully young people who are curious about drugs after seeing this blog will think twice before trying them.

#### **Physic**

# Investigation of the effects of mass and elongation in bungee jump

The aim of this investment is to find the height that a player (object) should jump from in bungee jump. The essay was in an attempt to investigate on three levels: first is to find the variation of elongation with tension force, showing three stages, when the elongation is small, the tension force changes at slower and slower rate with elongation. At the second stage, it changes at nearly a constant rate with elongation, followed by a higher and higher rate with larger elongation. In the second part, the range in which elongation varies linearly with tension force was studied, a linear equation with R squared value (0.9964) was induced. Secondly, the conservation of energy was applied to find the relationship between elongation and mass of jumping object. Overall, a general formula was established to figure out the range of the mass of jumping object within the linear range of elongation. Thirdly, according to the results obtained from the investigation, the suggesting height for any mass of object within the range can be found, as a result, a simulated bungee experience on Barbie was designed as a practical application.



"Tell me and I forget. Teach me and I remember. Involve me and I learn." -Benjamin Franklin

#### Research

#### **Mathmatic**

#### Do you really know about MARIJUANA?

The article focuses on drug abuse. The sources referenced are the song "Hotel California", an article pub lished by National Institution on Drug Abuse, and a blog about marijuana legalization and regulation. From these materials I found that western countries are more tolerant towards marijuana compared to the Asian ones. Since blog is widely used and effectively targeted at a particular community, I plan to write a blog to provide both sides of marijuana, combining with relevant historical facts to explain the difference. Hopefully young people who are curious about drugs after seeing this blog will think twice before trying them.

#### Chemistry

# Investigation of the effects of mass and elongation in bungee jump

The aim of this investment is to find the height that a player (object) should jump from in bungee jump. The essay was in an attempt to investigate on three levels: first is to find the variation of elongation with tension force, showing three stages, when the elongation is small, the tension force changes at slower and slower rate with elongation. At the second stage, it changes at nearly a constant rate with elongation, followed by a higher and higher rate with larger elongation. In the second part, the range in which elongation varies linearly with tension force was studied, a linear equation with R squared value (0.9964) was induced. Secondly, the conservation of energy was applied to find the relationship between elongation and mass of jumping object. Overall, a general formula was established to figure out the range of the mass of jumping object within the linear range of elongation. Thirdly, according to the results obtained from the investigation, the suggesting height for any mass of object within the range can be found, as a result, a simulated bungee experience on Barbie was designed as a practical application.



"When you reach the end of your rope, tie a knot in it and hang on." -Franklin D. Roosevelt

#### **Acitivities**

#### **Food Recovery Club**

I join the club because I want to donate my passion to fight food waste and hunger by recovering perishable food that would otherwise go to waste from their campus dining halls and donating it to those in need. Normally, we met on Friday night and run food. Our goal is to change the norm from food waste to food recovery in the United States.

foodrecoverynetwork.org

#### Finance For the Community Club

Even though I am cs&design background, I interested in finance and strive to improve the lives of Boston Public High School students by teaching financial literacy and connecting inner-city high school students with college students to enable the transfer of ideas and experiences.

I take the finance class and some skills of public speaking during each club meeting. The curriculum covers a wide array of financial literacy topics - from understanding wants and needs to budgeting techniques, credit scores and credit card options, compound interest and loans, setting financial goals, preparing for the financial future of life after high school, and much more.

twitter.com/neuffc

#### **NUCSSA**

# Northeastern Chinese Student and Scholars Association

At the first semester of freshman, I joined the Outreach Department of NUCSSA. I enegaged to manage one of school social media account to promote ourr exciting student life in and off campus. Besides, I planned a series of activities such as the alumni exchange meeting to make good connections with each class of students.

www.neu.edu/cssa

